SOHAM PATKI

patki.s@northeastern.edu | (857) 204-8337 | linkedin.com/in/soham-patki/ | Boston, MA | https://sohampatki.github.io/Soham-Patki-s-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Data analytics professional with a Master's in Business Analytics and 2 years of experience at technology-driven organizations. Proficient with analytical tools like SQL, R and Tableau with a strong academic grounding in machine learning techniques, data visualization skills and database management. Seeking roles in data analytics, business analytics and business operations.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, Massachusetts Master of Science in Business Analytics Earlham College, Richmond, Indiana Bachelor of Arts in Economics Dec 2023

May 2020

SKILLS

- Tools: R, SQL (Oracle, MySQL), Python, Tableau, STATA, Excel, PowerBI
- Coursework: Data Mining (supervised and unsupervised learning), Data Visualization and Dashboards, Database Management, Information Systems Design, Data Wrangling, Business Analytics Foundations
- Experience with: Data analysis, database design, data visualization, dashboard development, wireframing, report creation, business requirements documentation, machine learning, data cleaning and transformation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Safety-Kleen, Boston, Massachusetts Sales Analyst (Capstone Project)

Sep 2023 – Dec 2023

- Trained classification models to discover customer segments and product types associated with high risk of churn
- Identified trends in purchasing behavior and visualized them using Tableau to present insights to stakeholders
- Formulated actionable pricing strategies to reduce churn rates among high value customers by 15%

One Degree, San Francisco, California

Resource Specialist

Aug 2020 - Jul 2021

- Documented requirements elicited from non-profit partners and created custom datasets of 500+ services for each client, ensuring alignment with their case workers' needs
- Conducted data audits of 1000+ services in the company's database to ensure compliance with content guidelines
- Created and maintained county-specific guides on COVID testing and vaccination resources for One Degree's Californian users

PayActiv Inc, San Jose, California

May 2019 – Aug 2019

Data Analytics Intern

- Defined key metrics, designed wireframes and used SQL to develop monthly usage reports sent to PayActiv's 100+ B2B clients
- Automated several data transformation processes using R to streamline financial forecasting procedures
- · Visualized transaction data using R to identify seasonal trends in customer behavior

Dupatta World, Mumbai, India

May 2018 – Aug 2018

Implementation Analyst

- Translated requirements collected from stakeholders into functional specifications for a business intelligence tool tracking manufacturing operations and sales data
- Identified, documented, and escalated software defects to the developer team
- Provided feedback to simplify user workflows, improve sales insights and reduce time spent on data entry by 50%
- Provided technical support post-release and maintained written documentation to enable knowledge transfer